MICHAEL A. JONES

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EXECUTIVE PROFILE

Software Developer with proficient experience creating user-friendly full-stack applications and 2 years experience within the IT Industry. Exceptional communicator and problem solver, adept at motivating teams and cultivating relationships with internal and external stakeholders to drive specific initiatives.

CONTACT DETAILS

Mobile: 765.413.7723

Boise, ID

JonesyJava@gmail.com Github.com/JonesyJava

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML 5
- CSS
- JavaScript
- VUE.is 3
- Bootstrap
- Agile/SCRUM
- C#
- MongoDB
- Auth0
- MVC/MVVM
- RESTful API's
- Git

KEY WEB-BASED APPLICATION

710 - Personal Automotive Management Application

- Application that allows for personal fleet management providing the user the ability to retain all information for vehicle maintenance, visualization of overall fleet health, record receipts, and submit photos within one simple interface.
- Technologies Used Vue.js 3, HTML, CSS, Animate.CSS, MongoDB, JavaScript, Firebase, Auth0, Bootstrap, Node.js
- Application created within a group of 5 software developers, utilizing Agile/SCRUM Methodologies personally fulfilling the role of Back-end Developer, Frontend Developer, and Product Owner.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER STUDENT

CodeWorks | Boise, ID | Feb 2021 - April 2021

- Developed over 20 web-based applications within 13 weeks with over 520+ hours of programming experience
- Acquired hands-on experience with an array of object-oriented-programming languages and development frameworks utilizing and designing RESTful API's, Wireframing, and MVC/MVVM methods to successfully complete individual and teamwork based projects
- Experience utilizing Auth0, MongoDB, MySQL, and GitHub to create more advanced and complex web-based applications
- Learned and ultimately implemented Agile/SCRUM methodologies in a team of 5 developers over a sprint of 2 weeks; acting as the Product Owner

ASSISTANT BRANCH MANAGER

Enterprise Rent-A-Car | Boise, ID | Dec 2019 - Jan 2021

- Managed a daily 130+ vehicle fleet ensuring individual vehicle health, upkeep, and maintenance for consistent rental processes, averaging the highest daily occupancy at 93.7%.
- Promoted from Management Trainee to Management Assistant within first 6 months and then promoted a third time to Assistant Branch Manager within 3 months of previous promotion based on top overall performance
- Supported and lead a two-person operation for one of the largest Vehicle Rental locations in the Treasure Valley leveraging a consistent profit of \$51/Vehicle and \$245 weekly operating profit.
- Drove existing and established new long-lasting relationships with corporate accounts including Larry H Miller Collision, First Choice Collision - Boise, Franklin Auto Body, Power Engineers, among others, ensuring constant weekly and daily vehicle rentals.

TECHNICAL RECRUITER

TEKsystems | Boise, ID | Aug 2017 - Aug 2018

- Successful placements of 13 information technology professionals within contract, contract-to-hire, and direct hire positions for assigned business territory; Idaho, Montana, Washington, and Alaska
- Full lifecycle recruiting from business development, business, qualification, sourcing strategy, qualifying candidates, presentation of candidates to Directors and Senior level management, and maintained consistent communication between all stakeholders
- Developed proactive recruiting strategies to identify qualified candidates by using various networking tools including sponsoring and participating in local Information Technology user groups such as the following;
 - Net User Group Boise Chapter
 - Project Management Institute Western Idaho Chapter
 - Business Intelligence Group Boise Chapter
 - Tableau User Group Boise Chapter
 - Idaho Virtual Reality Council
- Negotiated fair market wages, benefits, and other terms and conditions of the employment contract with candidates
- Groomed relationships with business contracts, potential candidates, internal business advocates, and current contractors to gain industry knowledge, company insights, and obtain referrals

EDUCATION HISTORY

PURDUE UNIVERSITY

BA Forensic Anthropolgy | 2010 -2014

• Member, Phi Kappa Psi Fraternity, IN Delta Chapter

CODEWORKS

Certificate of Completion | Feb 2021 - April 2021

• Full Stack Software Development